Guide to the Divinity School, Yale University, Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Divinity School, Yale University, records
1825-1991
RU 167
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
40
The records consist of reports, minutes, lists, correspondence, subject files, daybooks, alumni records, student prize materials, and student data documenting the administrative operations of the Yale Divinity School.
Yale University. Divinity School
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 21-A (YRG 21-A), Central records and records of the dean of the Yale Divinity School.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the records is partially restricted. See Collection Contents for details.
Arrangement
The records are arranged by accession.
Scope and Contents
The records consist of reports, minutes, lists, correspondence, subject files, daybooks, alumni records, student prize materials, and student data documenting the administrative operations of the Yale Divinity School.
Religious education -- United States; Theology -- Study and teaching; Universities and colleges -- Administration; Yale College (1718-1887). Theological Department; Yale University -- Administration; Yale University -- Religion; Yale University -- Students; Yale University. Divinity School
- Records, 1825-1958; Accession 1964-A-001
  Conditions Governing Access
  The materials are open for research.
  - Accounts, 1910 July-1915 July (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Accounts, 1915 September-1930 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Admission Application, 1890s (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - constitutionAlumni Association minutes, records, 1895-1913 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Alumni Association records [also contains 1 page Records of Pastorate, Yale University], 1922-25 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Alumni Association records, 1927-1949 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Alumni Association Connecticut Branch, constitution, minutes, records, 1900-47 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Alumni Association Western Massachusetts records, 1940-41 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - correspondenceAlumni Class of 1885, 1937-41 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Alumni Class of 1887 autobiographical sketches (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Alumni Class of 1887 correspondence and biographical material, 1936-37 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Alumni Class of 1931 and reunion material, 1941-51 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Alumni correspondence, 1915-1920 (Box 3, Folder 13-14)
  - Alumni Lists, 1909-10 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Alumni Portrait Fund, correspondence, 1932, 36 (Box 3, Folder 16-19)
  - Alumni Portrait Fund, correspondence, 1945-48 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Alumni Portrait Fund, lists, (2 Volumes), 1948 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Annual Reports [from Theological Department and Faculty], 1869-86 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Beecher, Lyman Lectures on Preaching, 1871-1909 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Biblical and Semitic Departments record of students and graduates, 1886-1903 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Certificates of Admission to Church, 1823-32 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Certificates of Admission to Church, 1933-44 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Convocation Registration, 1925-36 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Convocation Guests Register, 1838-51 (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - Correspondence, 1835-1886 (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Education for Christian Service [by memebers of the faculty in commemoration of the school's 100th anniversary], 1922 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Examination Committees reports [examined students in the Theological Department], 1832-77 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - Expense Book, Student, 1900-05 (Box 6, Folder 32)
  - Faculty minutes and records, 1880-1919 (Box 6, Folder 33)
  - Faculty minutes and records, 1920-43 (Box 6, Folder 34)
  - Faculty minutes, 1942-45 (Box 7, Folder 35)
  - Faculty minutes extras, 1932-34 (Box 7, Folder 36)
  - Faculty resolutions to name endowed professorships, 1869, 1877 (Box 7, Folder 37)
  - Faculty statements, letters to the Corporation, etc., 1822-84, undated (Box 7, Folder 38)
  - Journal, 1905 (Box 7, Folder 39)
  - Library regulations, undated (Box 7, Folder 40)
  - Lowell Mason Society constitution, membership list, minutes, records, 1875-83 (Box 7, Folder 41)
  - Miscellaneous, 1814-1914 (Box 7, Folder 42)
  - Prizes. classes of, 1911-13 (Box 7, Folder 43)
  - Record of Studies, 1901 October -1904 June (Box 8, Folder 44)
  - Record of Studies, 1904 October -1907 June (Box 8, Folder 45)
  - Record of Studies, 1908 January -1911 (Box 8, Folder 46)
  - Record of Studies, 1924-25, 1929 (Box 10)
  - Society for Christion Research [in the Theological Seminary] constitution, members list, minutes, 1825-37 (Box 8, Folder 47)
  - Semitic and Biblical Club minutes and records, 1949-58 (Box 8, Folder 48)
  - Students, geographical distribution of living former students, undated (Box 9, Folder 49)
  - Students, biographical and demographic charts 6f students, circa 1900-1930 (Box 10)
  - Trowbridge Reference Library Catalogue, 1890 July (Box 9, Folder 50)
  - Trowbridge Reference Library index book, donations, 1870-1900 (Box 9, Folder 51)
  - Hright, Henry Cottage records vol. I, 1925-41 (Box 9, Folder 52)
  - Wright, Henry Cottage records vol. II, 1941-42 (Box 9, Folder 53)
  - Alumni Recrds (Box 10)
  - Record of Studies, 1924-25, 1929 (Box 10)
  - Students, biographical & demographic chart of students, circa 1900-1930 (Box 10)